because of the versatility having an
adjustable weight bench is one of the
best investments you can make for your
home gym and rep Fitness makes some of
my favorite adjustable benches on the
market but there's two in particular
that stick out compared to the rest I'm
talking about the Blackwing and the
ab5000 these benches are similar in
nature but there are some differences
that might make you lean to one over the
other so I think you know what time it
is today it's time for me to compare the
two and help you decide which one to buy
let's get to
it
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the Barb and garage gym and for today's
video I'm going to spend some time
talking about two of rep's best weight
benches the Blackwing and the ab5000
there's a lot to like about both of
these benches but you can definitely
make the case for one being better than
the other so my job today is to help you
decide which one to purchase but before
I do all that I just want to make sure
you guys know that we've reviewed a lot
of other weight benches on barb. comom
and we went ahead and made our own best
list so if you want to check that out
all you got to do is search barbend best
weight benches that article is going to
pull right up and you can browse our top
piics okay so I mentioned that these
benches are similar in nature and that's
definitely true there's a lot more
differences than there are similarities
so let's talk about the similarities
first these are both 11 gauge steel
weight benches so they have 1,000lb
weight capacity they're FID benches
meaning flat incline and Decline and
they both have you know reps patented
zero Gap mechanism for the seat that way
there's zero pad gap between the seat
and the backpad regardless of what angle
you're working with which is pretty much
a lifesaver I think we all can agree
that you know dealing with that awkward
pad Gap is just not the most fun and
enjoyable thing in the world okay now
when it comes to those differences all
right the main things here
rep actually redesigned the zero Gap
mechanism the knob should I say on the
Blackwing okay so with the ab5000 it's
underneath the Black Wing it's on the
side little bit you know easier easy
accessible I guess you could say right
the actual adjustment styles are
different the Blackwing is a ladder
style while the ab5000 is a pop pin
style and the amount of angles are
different as well which I'm going to dig
into in just a second that could
definitely play a factor in you know
which route you decide to go the
Blackwing has vertical storage while the
ab5000 does not rep also redesigned
their padding so it's kind of hard for
me to really be able to tell a
difference because ab5000 just kind of
has more wear on it I've had it for a
year and a half if not longer than that
while with the black Wing had it for a
handful of months but they have this
clean grip material you know it's
designed to grip you better and just
kind of be more comfortable in general
so definitely remember that now the
front foot design on these I like them
both but they're very different so with
the black Wing the front foot actually
kind of resembles a wing you know and
then with the
ab5000 it's it's a little different I
don't even know what kind of shape you
would describe it but I like how on
ab5000 you can get your feet closer
together and kind of get more
comfortable but the Black Wing I really
enjoy that handle placement I really
like how it's out in front I also enjoy
the fact that it's got a stainless steel
knurled handle it's easier it's more
accessible easier to grab and it also
makes the weight feel lighter all right
so the Blackwing ways 130 lb while the
ab5000 is 110 lb but I got to be honest
whenever I go to move both of these
around ab5000 feels heavier feels like
it's opposite so definitely remember
that could come into effect in in
different ways definitely just don't
forget it the nature of the decline with
these is also very different okay so I
forgot to mention you can purchase a leg
roller for both of these it's the same
one it's not like they're different
that's going to allow you to do decline
sit-ups Nordic curls all that good stuff
but with
ab5000 it's a little funky right so to
actually use this bench you know as a
decline bench you're going to have to
get in it in reverse if that makes sense
so your feet are going to have to go at
the top your head's going to have to be
down where your seat goes where the seat
is to do your decline bench presses so
something I really like about the Black
Wing is that you get to sit in it normal
and just lay back it's a negative 8
degree you know adjustment right there
and that allows you to do those decline
presses that's kind of my personal
preference the Black Wing has six colors
while ab5000 has five not that big of a
deal and then the Black Wing is also
going to cost you more money all right
so I'm going dig into that in a little
bit but right now it's about 150 bucks
[Music]
more okay so I kind of touched on it a
second ago but with the adjustments it's
very different all right so the
Blackwing is a lighter style adjustment
system while the ab5000 is a pop pin the
Blackwing also has more adjustments
available okay so the backpad has 12
different angles from 8 to 85° while the
seat pad has six different angles from
-10 to 45° and with the ab5000 you have
seven backpad angles from 0 to 90° and
five different seat pad angles from -5
to 45 now the actual framework of the
ab5000 is what's preventing the backpad
from you know going to a decline
position but as I mentioned earlier with
the leg roller you can turn this into an
FID bench okay so I prefer you know the
Black Wing just because it's already
built in you don't have to you know
spend an extra 100 110 bucks on that leg
roller and then you know kind of get in
the bench in a funky position just to do
some decline presses but you can
definitely still do it it might take you
a minute you to get the hang of it but
as I said you can definitely still do it
now as far as which adjustment you know
process is the best it's really just
personal preference I prefer the ladder
style I think it's easier to you know a
read the laser Andra
numbers on the actual you know ladder as
opposed to you know with the pop pin
Style with the ab5000 plus I think it's
easier to actually adjust it you know if
you want to you know go from 0o to you
know 45° for example you just grab the
back of the pad and you can pull it up
now with the ab5000 you got to squat
down pull out the pin Crank It Up I know
I'm being dramatic about it but that's
my personal preference all right and now
with the seat pad remember they both
have zero Gap technology so you don't
have to deal with any pad Gap what's
whatever I love that about these benches
I think that's what really you know sets
them apart from the rest of the pack but
with the black wi I really like how the
knobs on the side makes it a lot easier
you know if you're a little bit
uncomfortable whenever you go to sit
down you know sometimes whenever you're
adjusting these the they have to be you
know separated a little bit to get the
backpad you know where you want it and
the fact that you can just be sitting on
the actual padding and then just on the
side right here and scoot up or back
whatever it makes it just easier it's
not that bad with the ab5000 you just
reach underneath it's just you know a
little bit more difficult I guess now
just because I prefer the ladder style
it doesn't you know mean that it's
Superior it's just my personal
preference there's a lot of people out
there you know that prefer the pop pin
style and I definitely get that as well
and then when it comes you know down to
those angles you know you get more
versatility with the black Ling so you
that's definitely something that you
want to you know keep in mind whenever
you go to make your purchase you know
especially between these two and
speaking of making a purchase remember
the Black Wing is going to cost you more
money all right so black wings right
around 600 bucks with the ab5000 it's
listed as 600 but got a strike through
it and listed as 450 it's been that way
for a while I'm kind of assuming you
know what they say about assuming you
don't really want to do it all the time
but right now I am kind of assuming that
rep's going to keep the ab5000 around
450 bucks 150 bucks yeah I mean that's
that's an a significant Gap right you
can take that 150 and and you know use
it elsewhere right with you know an
adjustable kettle Bell System maybe a
new barbell whatever it is right so you
know if money is really your you know
main deciding factor between these two
weight benches then I mean yeah it
probably does make the most sense to you
know save that 150 and go after the
ab5000 but my opinion you know 600 the
Black Wing you know the quality of it
everything that it entails it's not like
you're getting robbed or anything like
that that's still a pretty solid price
tag
okay so now it's kind of time for the
hard part right and it's time to talk
about which one you should buy all right
so I personally don't think you can go
wrong with either one of these weight
benches just want to go ahead and and
throw that out there but there's a few
factors that you definitely need to
prioritize first being the money all
right both of these are kind of
expensive right Black Wing 600 bucks AB
5450 now the fact that rep you know does
not charge for shipping is huge that's
one of my favorite things about rep but
you know 150 bucks that's like I
mentioned a minute ago you know that's a
significant Gap you can do plenty of
different things with 150 bucks like I
said wiggle room for your budget with
your home gym equipment just stay within
your budget it's kind of it right there
right now vertical storage is also you
know a big thing in my opinion now it's
not the case with everybody you know
some people have a ton of room to work
with but a lot of people don't so that
vertical storage definitely comes into
play and the fact that the Blackwing has
that that is definitely you know a plus
I would say another thing here this is
probably the most important in my
opinion is the actual adjustments that
are available got to worry about the
adjustment style you know which one you
like the best but the available
adjustments is huge remember you have 12
back pad adjustments with the black wi
to seven with the ab5000 and then to do
decline work you have to attach the leg
roller and then get in the ab5000 in
reverse order just to be able to work in
those decline presses so honestly y'all
for me you know the actual Simplicity
and ease of use everything with the
Blackwing just kind of you know Takes
the Cake for me here and kind of makes
me go to the Blackwing over the ab5000
but honestly it's kind of like splitting
hairs and I definitely once again don't
think you can go wrong with either one
of these benches just prioritize your
specific
needs that's all I got for y'all today
on this comparison between the rep
Fitness Blackwing and the ab5000 these
are two of my favorite benches on the
market you can't go wrong with both of
them but as I mentioned I kind of got to
give the nod to the Black Wing just
because of the Simplicity thanks for
hanging out with me I hope this video
was helpful and I was able to highlight
everything you need to know about both
of these benches as always stay posted
for my next video but for now head over
to barb. comom cuz we have a full
written article comparing these two
benches all you got to do is search
barbend rep Blackwing versus ab5000 and
it's going to pull right up for you I'll
catch youall next
[Music]
time